Hi everyone, this is Gasser Ahmed.
Welcome to this presentation where I’m going
to talk about the AI technology strategy for
the Lawn Buddy app.
I am building an AI-powered strategy for a
lawn service startup company called Lawn Buddy
that allows lawn owners to input information
about their lawn to help determining the type
of service the lawn needs then customers will
be able to schedule and confirm their lawn
service appointment
Lawn Buddy however faces few strategic problems
for instance landscape maintenance involves
multiple tasks that must be performed properly
at the right time to avoid losing the advantage
of natural process.
In addition, scheduling and dispatching landscapers
on time with the right equipment makes a big
difference to operations and profitability.
Also, since the business is seasonal, keeping
the equipment safe and in a ready-to-operate
condition when the crew needs them at the
job site is a challenge and requires proper
usage and maintenance on a routine basis.
Lastly Green industry regulations whether
it is related to the use of pesticides and
fertilizers, or the equipment and pollution
levels is a big challenge for Lawn Buddy.
For the previous problems Lawn Buddy should
use object recognition to scan and evaluate
the lawn to determine the right time to perform
lawn maintenance tasks.
Lawn Buddy should also use an equipment maintenance
program to track the equipment in use in real-time
and notify the crew member about the upcoming
maintenance lastly Lawn Buddy should have
the right inspection tools, historical records,
and a knowledge-base to help in keeping up
with the regulatory standards
Lawn Buddy is targeting early adopters as
they are happy to test the product, provide
feedback, and hope to simplify everyday tasks.
The targeted early adopters will be those
who do not have time to dedicate to lawn maintenance
or physically unable to provide care to their
lawn like the elderly, sick individuals or
disabled persons in addition to those who
do not have lawn care tools and seek lawn
services.
Lawn Buddy uses a principle of machine and
deep learning called object recognition where
computer vision technique allows users to
identify and locate objects in an image.
Lawn Buddy has a thorough dataset of all types
of lawns like lawn color or quality blade
length lawn size, and lawn terrain.
Having this dataset allows us to have the
most accurate reading of the image recognition.
By analyzing that dataset Lawn Buddy uses
the criteria of computer vision in order to
break down the classification, localization
and tagging.
Lawn buddy uses the classification feature
to detect the lawn, localization to determine
lawn size, and tagging to further find the
lawn quality which is measured through lawn
color and blade length which determines when
the lawn needs to be trimmed.
The value network of Lawn Buddy consists of
multiple key players like homeowners who use
the tool to provide information about lawn,
schedule appointments, and confirm payments.
Credit Payment Service, which enables secured
payment transactions between homeowners and
lawn professionals.
Lawn Professionals, who use tool to confirm
appointments and provide reports about services.
Home Improvement Stores, that enable new lawn
mowing services to lawn professionals.
Homeowners Insurance, that reduces lawn care
costs by paying for lawn damage caused by
an earthquake or a flood.
Data Analytics, by selling data to third parties
for research and additional services.
AI Engineers who analyze data to provide algorithms
improvements and service solutions and lastly
those who use the app to promote and sell
other services to stakeholders.
So as a wrap up Lawn Buddy is a pioneering
idea.
By mobilizing lawn maintenance, the company
actively implements ease and efficiency.
At Lawn Buddy the lawn professional comes
to the customer knowing exactly what needs
to be done where the process is completely
contact-free Lawn Buddy also projects many
goals to further grow the company for year
1 the company plans to convert into a fully
functioning service then after 5 years, lawn
buddy plans to broaden service offerings and
after 10 years the plan is to broaden geographic
locations and move at a national level.
Thank you for watching!